Friends, in today's video we are going to analyze Aaa Lord
General Insurance Company Limited
in detail. So let's
start with the returns. The 1-day
return has been around 6%. Here, the 1-
week return is 7.6%. In 1 month, the return has been 4.4%.
In 3 months, it is
5.4%. In 1 year, it is 37.5%. And if we look at the 5-year return, it is
43.2%, which is a good return.
Friends, let's now look at some highlights of the stock,
such as the stock sentiment,
which is neutral. Right now, the
market pricing is slightly
overvalued. We will discuss why later.
Now friends, we can look at its spot analysis,
where if we look at the strength, we can
see six strengths. Three-
year return of
9.90%. In 3 years, friends, it has given a return of 9.19%,
which is a good return. Revenue has
grown impressively over the last
quarter by 3.52% over the past
quarter.  So as per the previous quarter, the
revenue of this quarter has been higher at 3.52.
Net profit has grown
impressively over the last year by 10.9.6 over
the past year. So, if we
look at the last year as per the previous year, then the
net profit of 10.9 is higher.
Net profit has grown impressively over
the last quarter by 20.4.1 over the
past quarter. So the net profit of the last quarter is
good, it is at 20.4.
Impressive RO is of 17.1.
Impressive RO is of 22.7. What is the weakness,
friends, it does not give good dividend, it is
close to 0.66. What is the opportunity, change
in promoter selling by 3.27 indicates
opportunity. So, friends, the promoter has
increased his holding here and
when the promoter increases his holding in any company, then
understand that something good is going to happen
in the company because most of the
friends, what is in the future  The plan is going to be
what the future is going to be,
only the promoter knows what the threat is, so
DI has reduced its holding at 2.45.
Now friends, look at the performance here, if you
look at the 52-week low and the 52-week high, it is close to the 52-week
high. Today's low high is also close to today's
high. Now let's
look at the fundamentals, like the P is 42.82,
whereas the P of the sector is 24, so it is trading at double the
price of the sector, that is why friends, we had
said that the stock is overvalued. The dividend is
close to 0.7 per market. The market cap is Rs 8168 crore.
Lord General Insurance Company
Limited is the fourth largest player in the
general insurance sector. It offers a well-
diversified range of products and risk
management solutions through multiple
distribution channels. It has issued 2.5
crore insurance policies on average over the
last three years. So, friends, if we look at the last two to three years,
they have opened insurance policies worth around Rs 2.5 crore to Rs 2.5 crore every year, so a
good number of friends.  They have a
market cap in insurance and
they also have a good market share, so
you can see the revenue, there was nothing in 2020, nothing
in 2021 as well, friends, in 2022,
friends, there was no revenue in 2021 due to corona,
now in 2022 it is
1683 crores, in 2023 it is 8870 crores
and in 2024 it is 20602 crores, so
friends, the revenue is increasing every year and is becoming quite good,
see the net profit, in 2020 it was
1193 crores, in 2021 it was 1473 crores,
in 2022 it was 1271 crores, then in 2023 it was 1729
crores, so it increased by 500 crores friends,
then in 2024 it was 1918 crores, so here
friends, the net profit is quite good,
you should also consider it, now if
you look at the share holding, the promoter has it at 47.5, but at
47.99  FII has it at 23.40,
Domestic Institution has it at 17.50
and Retail & Others has it at 11.50. Now
friends, let us see the RO of some of them, like
its RO was 20 in 2020, 21.7 in 2021,
15.4 in 2022, 17.7 in 2023 and
is also close to 17.2 in 2024. You can also see the RO, it is
quite good, it is at 27 in 20 and 21,
then it decreased a bit in 19, 22, it was at
19 in 23 and at 23 in 24. You can see the RO, it was at
19 in 20, close to 20 in 2021, at
14 in 2022, close to 17 in 2023
and is also quite good at 16 in 24.
Earnings  But if you look at the stock from here, friends, it is
quite good, it was 26 in 2020, after that it
became 32 in 21, then it decreased a little in 25,
after that it started increasing continuously friends,
see here it was 25 in 2020, then it
is 35 in 2023 and 38 in 2024, friends, if
you also want to invest in it, then
invest only after analyzing it in detail.